"<GPE>MOSCOW</GPE>, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.The <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> armed forces lost <CARDINAL>more than 300</CARDINAL> servicemen in the <GPE>Kursk</GPE> area over <DATE>the past day</DATE>, and <CARDINAL>21,900</CARDINAL> since the start of the hostilities in the region, <ORG>the Russian Defense Ministry</ORG> reported.The <NORP>Russian</NORP> marines have destroyed a <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> reconnaissance unit in the <GPE>Kursk</GPE> border region, the military told <ORG>TASS</ORG>.<ORG>TASS</ORG> has summed up information about the situation.- The <NORP>Russian</NORP> military repelled <CARDINAL>five</CARDINAL> enemy attacks towards the settlements of <GPE>Lyubimovka</GPE>, <GPE>Malaya Loknya</GPE>, <GPE>Novaya Sorochina</GPE> and <GPE>Kremyanoye</GPE>.- <GPE>Russia</GPE>'s <ORG>Battlegroup North</ORG> units continued offensive operations and destroyed <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> formations in the areas of <GPE>Daryino</GPE>, <GPE>Lyubimovka</GPE>, <GPE>Tolsty Lug</GPE>, <GPE>Novy Put</GPE> and <GPE>Plekhovo</GPE>.- <ORG>The Russian Armed Forces</ORG> struck clusters of manpower and equipment in the areas of <GPE>Bondarevka</GPE>, <GPE>Goncharovka</GPE>, <GPE>Daryino</GPE>, <GPE>Zazulevka</GPE>, <GPE>Kurilovka</GPE>, <GPE>Leonidovo</GPE>, <GPE>Lyubimovka</GPE>, <GPE>Malaya Loknya</GPE>, <GPE>Martynovka</GPE>, <GPE>Makhnovka</GPE>, Nikolayevo-<GPE>Daryino</GPE>, <GPE>Novy Put</GPE>, <GPE>Nizhny Klin</GPE>, <GPE>Novoivanovka</GPE>, <GPE>Orlovka</GPE>, <GPE>Plekhovo</GPE>, <GPE>Sverdlikovo</GPE>, <GPE>Tolsty Lug</GPE> and <GPE>Cherkasskoye Porechnoye</GPE>.- Tactical air and missile forces struck <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> reserves in the <GPE>Sumy</GPE> region.- The operation to wipe out the enemy forces continues.- Over <DATE>the day</DATE>, the enemy lost <CARDINAL>more than 300</CARDINAL> servicemen, <CARDINAL>13</CARDINAL> units of armored vehicles, among them <CARDINAL>five</CARDINAL> tanks, <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> infantry fighting vehicles, <CARDINAL>five</CARDINAL> armored combat vehicles, as well as <CARDINAL>4</CARDINAL> pieces of artillery, a multiple rocket launcher, a mortar, an electronic warfare station and <CARDINAL>four</CARDINAL> motor vehicles.<CARDINAL>One</CARDINAL> <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> serviceman surrendered as a prisoner of war (POW).- Since the beginning of hostilities in <LOC>the Kursk Region</LOC>, <GPE>Kiev</GPE> has lost over <CARDINAL>21,900</CARDINAL> servicemen, <CARDINAL>144</CARDINAL> tanks, <CARDINAL>69</CARDINAL> infantry fighting vehicles, <CARDINAL>98</CARDINAL> armored personnel carriers, <CARDINAL>897</CARDINAL> armored combat vehicles, <CARDINAL>594</CARDINAL> motor vehicles, <CARDINAL>181</CARDINAL> artillery guns, <CARDINAL>34</CARDINAL> multiple rocket launchers, including <CARDINAL>eight</CARDINAL> <PRODUCT>HIMARS</PRODUCT> and <CARDINAL>six</CARDINAL> <GPE>US-made</GPE> <PRODUCT>MLRS</PRODUCT>, <CARDINAL>nine</CARDINAL> launchers of anti-aircraft missile systems, <CARDINAL>five</CARDINAL> transport and loading vehicles, <CARDINAL>47</CARDINAL> electronic warfare stations, <CARDINAL>nine</CARDINAL> counter-battery radars, <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> air defense radars, <CARDINAL>22</CARDINAL> pieces of engineering and other equipment, including <CARDINAL>13</CARDINAL> engineering demolition vehicles, a <PRODUCT>UR-77</PRODUCT> demining unit, and <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> armored repair vehicles.- The <NORP>Russian</NORP> marines destroyed a <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> reconnaissance unit in the <GPE>Kursk</GPE> border region, taking <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> military personnel as POWs, the military told <ORG>TASS</ORG>."
"<GPE>MOSCOW</GPE>, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.<NORP><GPE>Russia</GPE>n</NORP> forces delivered <CARDINAL>38</CARDINAL> strikes by precision weapons, including <PRODUCT>Kinzhal</PRODUCT> hypersonic missiles and unmanned aerial vehicles at <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> oil and gas and energy sites and military airfields over <DATE>the week</DATE> in the special military operation in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>, <GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <ORG>Defense Ministry</ORG> reported on <DATE>Friday</DATE>.\"On <DATE>October 5-11</DATE>, <ORG>the Russian Armed Forces</ORG> delivered <CARDINAL>38</CARDINAL> combined strikes by precision weapons, including <PRODUCT>Kinzhal</PRODUCT> air-launched hypersonic ballistic missiles and attack unmanned aerial vehicles.The strikes targeted oil and gas and energy sites providing for the operation of <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> military-industrial enterprises, and also military airfield infrastructure.In addition, the strikes hit production workshops and storage facilities of naval drones and unmanned aerial vehicles, fuel depots, ammunition and materiel warehouses and temporary deployment sites of <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army units, nationalist formations and foreign mercenaries,\" the ministry said in a statement.The <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army lost <CARDINAL>almost 14,500</CARDINAL> troops in battles with <NORP><GPE>Russia</GPE>n</NORP> forces in all the frontline areas over <DATE>the week</DATE>, according to the latest data on the special military operation in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> released by <GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <ORG>Defense Ministry</ORG>.The latest data indicate that the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army suffered <CARDINAL>more than 2,090</CARDINAL> casualties from <GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <EVENT>Battlegroup North</EVENT>, <CARDINAL>roughly 2,920</CARDINAL> casualties from <EVENT>the Battlegroup West</EVENT>, <CARDINAL>about 4,790</CARDINAL> casualties from <EVENT>the Battlegroup South</EVENT>, <CARDINAL>around 3,370</CARDINAL> casualties from <FAC>the Battlegroup Center</FAC>, <CARDINAL>780</CARDINAL> casualties from <EVENT>the Battlegroup East</EVENT> and <CARDINAL>480</CARDINAL> casualties from <EVENT>the Battlegroup Dnepr</EVENT>, with its total <DATE>weekly</DATE> losses amounting to <CARDINAL>14,430</CARDINAL> personnel.<GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <ORG>Battlegroup North</ORG> liberated the settlements of <GPE>Novaya Sorochina</GPE> and <GPE>Pokrovsky</GPE> in <LOC>the Kursk Region</LOC> and inflicted <CARDINAL>roughly 2,090</CARDINAL> casualties on <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> troops in its area of responsibility over <DATE>the week</DATE>, the ministry reported.\"During <DATE>the week</DATE>, <ORG>Battlegroup North</ORG> units continued an operation to destroy <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> armed formations in <LOC>the Kursk Region</LOC>, in which they liberated the settlements of <GPE>Novaya Sorochina</GPE> and <GPE>Pokrovsky</GPE>,\" the ministry said.Over <DATE>the week</DATE>, <NORP>Russian</NORP> aircraft, unmanned aerial vehicles and artillery inflicted casualties on <CARDINAL>six</CARDINAL> mechanized brigades, a tank brigade, <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> air assault brigades of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army, a marine infantry brigade, <CARDINAL>four</CARDINAL> territorial defense brigades and a <ORG>National Guard</ORG> brigade, it specified.<GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <ORG>Battlegroup North</ORG> units also inflicted damage in the <GPE>Volchansk</GPE> and <GPE>Liptsy</GPE> directions in <GPE>the Kharkov Region</GPE> on manpower and military hardware of a motorized infantry brigade, a jaeger brigade, an air assault brigade of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army, <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> territorial defense brigades and a <ORG>National Guard</ORG> brigade, the ministry said.The <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army’s losses in the <ORG>Battlegroup North</ORG> area of responsibility amounted to <CARDINAL>more than 2,090</CARDINAL> personnel, <CARDINAL>nine</CARDINAL> tanks, <CARDINAL>32</CARDINAL> armored combat vehicles, <CARDINAL>26</CARDINAL> motor vehicles, a <NORP>Czech-made</NORP> <PRODUCT>Vampire</PRODUCT> multiple rocket launcher and <CARDINAL>25</CARDINAL> field artillery guns, it said.In addition, <NORP>Russian</NORP> forces destroyed <CARDINAL>five</CARDINAL> electronic warfare and counterbattery radar stations and <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> field ammunition depots of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army over <DATE>the week</DATE>, the ministry said.<GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <ORG>Battlegroup West</ORG> repelled <CARDINAL>23</CARDINAL> <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army counterattacks and inflicted <CARDINAL>more than 2,900</CARDINAL> casualties on enemy troops in its area of responsibility over <DATE>the week</DATE>, the ministry reported.\"Over <DATE>the week</DATE>, <PRODUCT>Battlegroup West</PRODUCT> units continued advancing deep into the enemy’s defenses and gained more advantageous positions.They inflicted casualties on formations of <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> tank and <CARDINAL>six</CARDINAL> mechanized brigades, an assault brigade of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army, <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> territorial defense brigades and <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> <ORG>National Guard</ORG> brigades.They repelled <CARDINAL>23</CARDINAL> counterattacks by assault groups of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army,\" the ministry said.The <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army’s losses in that frontline area over <DATE>the week</DATE> amounted to <CARDINAL>2,920</CARDINAL> personnel, <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> tanks, <CARDINAL>16</CARDINAL> other armored combat vehicles, among them <CARDINAL>eight</CARDINAL> <GPE>US-made</GPE> <PRODUCT>M<CARDINAL>11</CARDINAL>3</PRODUCT> armored personnel carriers, <CARDINAL>46</CARDINAL> motor vehicles and <CARDINAL>35</CARDINAL> field artillery guns, including <CARDINAL>11</CARDINAL> <ORG>NATO-supplied</ORG> <QUANTITY>155mm</QUANTITY> self-propelled artillery systems and howitzers, it specified.In addition, <NORP>Russian</NORP> forces destroyed <CARDINAL>13</CARDINAL> electronic warfare and counterbattery radar stations and <CARDINAL>22</CARDINAL> field ammunition depots of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army over <DATE>the week</DATE>, the ministry said.<GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <ORG>Battlegroup South</ORG> liberated <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> communities in <GPE>the Donetsk People’s Republic</GPE> over <DATE>the week</DATE>, the ministry reported.\"<ORG>Battlegroup South</ORG> units liberated the settlements of <GPE>Zhelannoye Vtoroye</GPE> and <GPE>Ostrovskoye</GPE> in <GPE>the Donetsk People’s Republic</GPE> as a result of decisive operations,\" the ministry said.<GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <ORG>Defense Ministry</ORG> reported on <DATE>October 8</DATE> that <ORG>Battlegroup South</ORG> units had liberated the settlement of <GPE>Zoryanoye Pervoye</GPE> in <GPE>the Donetsk People’s Republic</GPE>.Over <DATE>the week</DATE>, <ORG>Battlegroup South</ORG> units inflicted damage on manpower and military hardware of <CARDINAL>five</CARDINAL> mechanized brigades, a motorized infantry brigade, <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> infantry brigades, an assault brigade, a mountain assault brigade, an air assault brigade and <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> airmobile brigades of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army, a territorial defense brigade and <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> <ORG>National Guard</ORG> brigades.They repelled <CARDINAL>22</CARDINAL> counterattacks by <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> assault groups, it specified.The <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army’s losses in that frontline area over <DATE>the week</DATE> amounted to <CARDINAL>4,790</CARDINAL> personnel, <CARDINAL>four</CARDINAL> armored combat vehicles, <CARDINAL>53</CARDINAL> motor vehicles and <CARDINAL>45</CARDINAL> field artillery guns, among them <CARDINAL>37</CARDINAL> Western-made weapons, it said.In addition, <NORP>Russian</NORP> forces destroyed <CARDINAL>five</CARDINAL> electronic warfare stations and <CARDINAL>10</CARDINAL> field ammunition depots of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army over <DATE>the week</DATE>, the ministry said.<GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <FAC>Battlegroup Center</FAC> liberated the settlement of <GPE>Grodovka</GPE> in <GPE>the Donetsk People’s Republic</GPE>, repulsed <CARDINAL>58</CARDINAL> <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> counterattacks and inflicted <CARDINAL>roughly 3,370</CARDINAL> casualties on enemy troops in its area of responsibility over <DATE>the week</DATE>, the ministry reported.\"<FAC>Battlegroup Center</FAC> units liberated the settlement of <GPE>Grodovka</GPE> in <GPE>the Donetsk People’s Republic</GPE> in active operations.They inflicted casualties on formations of a tank brigade, <CARDINAL>seven</CARDINAL> mechanized brigades, a motorized infantry brigade, <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> infantry brigades, a jaeger brigade, an airborne brigade of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army, <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> marine infantry brigades, <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> territorial defense brigades and <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> <ORG>National Guard</ORG> brigades.They repulsed <CARDINAL>58</CARDINAL> counterattacks by enemy assault groups,\" the ministry said.The <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army’s losses in that frontline area over <DATE>the week</DATE> amounted to <CARDINAL>3,370</CARDINAL> personnel, <CARDINAL>four</CARDINAL> tanks, among them <NORP>German-made</NORP> <PRODUCT>Leopard</PRODUCT> and <NORP>French-made</NORP> <PRODUCT>AMX-10</PRODUCT> tanks and <CARDINAL>11</CARDINAL> other armored combat vehicles, including an M<CARDINAL>11</CARDINAL>3 armored personnel carrier and a <PRODUCT>Bradley</PRODUCT> infantry fighting vehicle of <GPE>US</GPE> manufacture, it specified.In addition, <NORP>Russian</NORP> forces destroyed <CARDINAL>27</CARDINAL> motor vehicles and <CARDINAL>26</CARDINAL> field artillery guns of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army over <DATE>the week</DATE>, it said.<GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <ORG>Battlegroup East</ORG> liberated the settlement of <GPE>Zolotaya Niva</GPE> in <GPE>the Donetsk People’s Republic</GPE> over <DATE>the week</DATE>, the ministry reported.\"<ORG>Battlegroup East</ORG> units liberated the settlement of <GPE>Zolotaya Niva</GPE> in <GPE>the Donetsk People’s Republic</GPE> as a result of well-coordinated operations,\" the ministry said.Over <DATE>the week</DATE>, <ORG>Battlegroup East</ORG> units inflicted damage on manpower and military hardware of <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> mechanized brigades, a motorized infantry brigade of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army, <CARDINAL>four</CARDINAL> territorial defense brigades and a <ORG>National Guard</ORG> brigade, it specified.<GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <ORG>Battlegroup East</ORG> inflicted <CARDINAL>roughly 780</CARDINAL> casualties on <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> troops in its area of responsibility over <DATE>the week</DATE>, the ministry reported.<ORG>Battlegroup East</ORG> units also repelled <CARDINAL>10</CARDINAL> counterattacks by assault groups of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army over <DATE>the week</DATE>, it said.The <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army’s losses in that frontline area over <DATE>the week</DATE> amounted to <CARDINAL>780</CARDINAL> personnel, <CARDINAL>five</CARDINAL> armored combat vehicles, among them two <GPE>US-made</GPE> <PRODUCT>M113</PRODUCT> armored personnel carriers and <CARDINAL>51</CARDINAL> motor vehicles, the ministry specified.In addition, <NORP>Russian</NORP> forces destroyed <CARDINAL>16</CARDINAL> field artillery guns of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army over <DATE>the week</DATE>, including <CARDINAL>12</CARDINAL> <ORG>NATO-produced</ORG> weapons, it said.<GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <PRODUCT>Battlegroup Dnepr</PRODUCT> inflicted <CARDINAL>roughly 480</CARDINAL> casualties on <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> troops and destroyed <CARDINAL>four</CARDINAL> enemy ammunition depots in its area of responsibility over <DATE>the week</DATE>, the ministry reported.\"<EVENT>Battlegroup Dnepr</EVENT> units inflicted casualties on formations of <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> mechanized brigades, an infantry brigade, a mountain assault brigade of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army, a marine infantry brigade and <CARDINAL>four</CARDINAL> territorial defense brigades,\" the ministry said.The <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army’s losses in that frontline area over <DATE>the week</DATE> amounted to <CARDINAL>480</CARDINAL> personnel, <CARDINAL>27</CARDINAL> motor vehicles and <CARDINAL>14</CARDINAL> field artillery guns, it specified.In addition, <NORP>Russian</NORP> forces destroyed <CARDINAL>seven</CARDINAL> electronic warfare and counterbattery radar stations and <CARDINAL>four</CARDINAL> field ammunition depots of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army over <DATE>the week</DATE>, the ministry said.<CARDINAL>More than 40</CARDINAL> <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> soldiers surrendered to <NORP>Russian</NORP> troops over <DATE>the week</DATE>, the ministry reported.\"During <DATE>the week</DATE>, <CARDINAL>43</CARDINAL> <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> servicemen surrendered at the engagement line,\" the ministry said.<NORP>Russian</NORP> air defense forces destroyed <CARDINAL>603</CARDINAL> <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> fixed-wing unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs), <CARDINAL>33</CARDINAL> rockets of the <GPE>US-made</GPE> <PRODUCT>HIMARS</PRODUCT> multiple launch rocket system and <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> <NORP>American</NORP> <PRODUCT>ATACMS</PRODUCT> missiles over <DATE>the week</DATE>, the ministry reported.\"Over <DATE>the week</DATE>, air defense capabilities shot down <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> <GPE>US-made</GPE> <PRODUCT>ATACMS</PRODUCT> operational/tactical missiles, <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> <NORP>French-made</NORP> <PRODUCT>Hammer</PRODUCT> guided aerial bombs, an <PRODUCT>S-200</PRODUCT> surface-to-air missile converted for striking ground targets, <CARDINAL>33</CARDINAL> <GPE>US-made</GPE> <PRODUCT>HIMARS</PRODUCT> rockets and <CARDINAL>603</CARDINAL> fixed-wing unmanned aerial vehicles,\" the ministry said.Overall, <ORG>the Russian Armed Forces</ORG> have destroyed <CARDINAL>646</CARDINAL> <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> warplanes, <CARDINAL>283</CARDINAL> helicopters, <CARDINAL>33,419</CARDINAL> unmanned aerial vehicles, <CARDINAL>582</CARDINAL> surface-to-air missile systems, <CARDINAL>18,607</CARDINAL> tanks and other armored combat vehicles, <CARDINAL>1,470</CARDINAL> multiple rocket launchers, <CARDINAL>15,988</CARDINAL> field artillery guns and mortars and <CARDINAL>27,145</CARDINAL> special military motor vehicles since the start of the special military operation, the ministry reported."
"<GPE>HELSINKI</GPE>, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.<GPE>Finland</GPE>'s <ORG>National Bureau of Investigation</ORG> said it has completed its inquiry into <NORP>Russian</NORP> national <PERSON>Voislav Torden</PERSON> for alleged war crimes committed in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> in <DATE>2014</DATE>, the organization said in a press release.On <DATE>December 18, 2023</DATE>, <ORG>the Helsinki District Court</ORG> ordered the detention of <PERSON>Torden</PERSON> on suspicion of committing a war crime in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> under aggravating circumstances.\"<ORG>The National Bureau of Investigation</ORG> has completed a criminal inquiry into suspected war crimes committed in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> in <DATE>2014</DATE>.<CARDINAL>One</CARDINAL> individual is suspected of committing several war crimes, including war crimes in aggravated circumstances,\" the statement reads.It specifies that evidence gathered by criminal investigators will be handed over to prosecutors.\"Based on these files, the deputy attorney general will decide whether to prosecute the case,\" the police said.All charges must be filed by <DATE>October 31, 2024</DATE>.According to the arrest warrant, the alleged crimes were committed <DATE>between 2014 and 2015</DATE>.<PERSON>Torden</PERSON> was detained by <NORP>Finnish</NORP> border guards on <DATE>July 20, 2023</DATE>.Formerly known as <PERSON>Jan Petrovsky</PERSON>, <PERSON>Torden</PERSON> is a <NORP>Russian</NORP> citizen and is included on the sanctions lists of both <ORG>the European Union</ORG> and <ORG>the US Treasury Department</ORG>.The <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> authorities are seeking <PERSON>Torden</PERSON>'s extradition on charges related to alleged crimes committed in <GPE>Donbass</GPE>.The <NORP>Russian</NORP> embassy in <GPE>Finland</GPE> previously informed <ORG>TASS</ORG> that <NORP>Russian</NORP> diplomats are closely monitoring the situation and are prepared to protect <PERSON>Torden</PERSON>'s rights.His lawyer, <PERSON>Natalya Malgina</PERSON>, told <ORG>TASS</ORG> that she expects charges will indeed be filed.The ensuing trial should last <DATE>a couple of months</DATE>, she added.\"The fact that charges would be filed was evident from the moment <GPE>Finland</GPE> began criminal proceedings.Court dates have not been set, but the trial will last <DATE>a couple of months</DATE>,\" <PERSON>Malgina</PERSON> said."
"<GPE>MOSCOW</GPE>, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.More and more unexplained deaths of forcibly mobilized <NORP>Ukrainians</NORP> are occurring at military recruitment offices, representatives of the <FAC>Dozor</FAC> underground told <ORG>TASS</ORG>.\"<NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> law pretty much gives free rein to temporary recruitment centers to do anything they want, even in controversial situations, revealing the country's true politics - depravity.Currently, deaths at temporary recruitment centers are common,\" the representatives pointed out.They noted that <NORP>Ukrainians</NORP> now see the centers' employees \"as something problematic and malignant.\"Due to widespread public anger, many conscientious employees have left their jobs, only to be replaced by \"total scumbags\" with criminal records.\"Meanwhile, most of them have never even seen combat themselves,\" the underground group emphasized.It noted that the <GPE>Kiev</GPE> authorities find it easy to control these employees due to their lack of education."
"<PERSON>VIENTIANE</PERSON> /<GPE>Laos</GPE>/, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.<GPE>US</GPE> Secretary of <ORG>State</ORG> <PERSON>Antony Blinken</PERSON> said even as he didn’t speak directly with <NORP>Russian</NORP> Foreign Minister <PERSON>Sergey Lavrov</PERSON> on the sidelines of the <ORDINAL>19th</ORDINAL> <EVENT>East Asia Summit</EVENT> (<EVENT>EAS</EVENT>) the <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> top diplomats \"heard\" each other.\"With regard to Minister <PERSON>Lavrov</PERSON>, no, we didn't speak directly, but I was in the room when he made his intervention on behalf of <GPE>Russia</GPE>.He was in the room when I made my intervention on behalf of <GPE>the United States</GPE>,\" the top <GPE>US</GPE> diplomat told a news conference.\"So, I think it's safe to say that we heard each other,\" <PERSON>Blinken</PERSON> said adding that he didn’t hear \"anything new, unfortunately,\" about the <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> conflict from <GPE>Russia</GPE>.The annual <EVENT>East Asia Summit</EVENT> is held on the sidelines of meetings of <ORG>the Association of Southeast Asian Nations</ORG> (<ORG>ASEAN</ORG>).<DATE>Between 2005 and 20<CARDINAL>10</CARDINAL></DATE>, the venue brought together <CARDINAL>16</CARDINAL> countries, namely, <ORG>the <ORG>ASEAN</ORG>-Plus Three</ORG> (<ORG>APT</ORG>), consisting of <CARDINAL>10</CARDINAL> <ORG>ASEAN</ORG> member states (<GPE>Brunei</GPE>, <GPE>Cambodia</GPE>, <GPE>Indonesia</GPE>, <GPE>Laos</GPE>, <GPE>Malaysia</GPE>, <GPE>Myanmar</GPE>, the <GPE>Philippines</GPE>, <GPE>Singapore</GPE>, <GPE>Thailand</GPE>, and <GPE>Vietnam</GPE>) and <GPE>China</GPE>, <GPE>Japan</GPE>, and <GPE>the Republic of Korea</GPE> (<GPE>ROK</GPE>) as well as <GPE>Australia</GPE>, <GPE>India</GPE>, and <GPE>New Zealand</GPE> which joined them.Since <DATE>2011</DATE>, <EVENT>the East Asia Summit</EVENT> has been attended by <GPE>Russia</GPE> and <GPE>the United States</GPE>."
"<GPE>DONETSK</GPE>, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.<NORP>Russian</NORP> drone operators have recorded cases of <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> barrier troops executing fellow servicemen who try to retreat from the frontlines, a serviceman from the battlegroup <ORG>South</ORG> said.\"During battles and so-called counterattacks, we sent our drones in to survey the situation.When the <NORP>Ukrainians</NORP> run out of ammunition and the situation gets bad, they try to retreat.They (the barrier troops - TASS) open fire on them with machine guns or something heavier.They are afraid to surrender to us for the same reason.<CARDINAL>Up to a dozen</CARDINAL> <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> servicemen are killed in each attack or counterattack,\" the serviceman said.He added that despite heavy losses, the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> barrier troops continue to kill their own soldiers with friendly fire."
"<GPE>WASHINGTON</GPE>, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.<NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> President <PERSON>Vladimir Zelensky</PERSON> is now more open to negotiating with <GPE>Russia</GPE> as <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>’s position has weakened, <ORG>The Washington Post</ORG> (<ORG>WaPo</ORG>) reported.According to the newspaper, <NORP>Western</NORP> diplomats \"have sensed\" that the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> leader \"has become more open to beginning negotiations with <GPE>Russia</GPE>, even as <GPE>Moscow</GPE>’s forces occupy <PERCENT>more than 20%</PERCENT> of <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> and are unlikely to cede any territory they currently control.\"Thus, <PERSON>Zelensky</PERSON> has said that \"<GPE>Russia</GPE> will be invited to the next peace summit that <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> plans to organize.\"<GPE>Kiev</GPE> has signaled the importance of ending the conflict as <GPE>Russia</GPE> has gained ground on the battlefield, <ORG>The Washington Post</ORG> wrote.<GPE>Kiev</GPE> has repeatedly rejected peace and mediation initiatives from <ORDINAL>third</ORDINAL> countries, saying it will only promote the so-called <PERSON>Zelensky</PERSON> formula.In <DATE>late September</DATE>, before leaving for a trip to <GPE>the United States</GPE>, <PERSON>Zelensky</PERSON> said he had some kind of \"plan\" to increase pressure on <GPE>Russia</GPE>, which he would first present to <GPE>US</GPE> leader <PERSON>Joe Biden</PERSON>.Later, <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> <ORG>Presidential Office</ORG> Head <PERSON>Andrey Yermak</PERSON> clarified that the \"plan\" will be presented to the country’s citizens without some \"sensitive\" details only after it has been shown to <GPE>Kiev</GPE>’s <NORP>Western</NORP> partners.On <DATE>June 14</DATE>, <NORP>Russian</NORP> President <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> at a meeting with <ORG>the Foreign Ministry</ORG> set out the country’s conditions for settling the situation in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>.Among them are the withdrawal of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> armed forces from <GPE>Donbass</GPE> and <GPE>Novorossiya</GPE> and <GPE>Kiev</GPE>’s refusal to join <ORG>NATO</ORG>.In addition, <GPE>Russia</GPE> wants all <NORP>Western</NORP> sanctions against it lifted and demands that <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> commit to a non-aligned and nuclear-free status.<GPE>Kiev</GPE> rejected the <NORP>Russian</NORP> peace plan.Following the launch of <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>’s incursion into the borderline region of <GPE>Kursk</GPE> on <DATE>August 6</DATE>, the <NORP>Russian</NORP> leader said it would make no sense to negotiate with a government attacking civilians."
"<GPE>LUGANSK</GPE>, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.<NORP>Russian</NORP> forces have pushed <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> troops out of their positions near the settlement of <GPE>Myasozharovka</GPE> and advanced by <QUANTITY>1.5 km</QUANTITY> to reach the administrative border of <GPE>the Lugansk People’s Republic</GPE> (<GPE>LPR</GPE>), military expert <PERSON>Andrey Marochko</PERSON> told <ORG>TASS</ORG> on <DATE>Friday</DATE>.\"Our troops have managed to push the enemy out of its positions southwest of the settlement of <GPE>Myasozharovka</GPE> in active combat operations.This has enabled <NORP>Russian</NORP> forces to advance by <QUANTITY>1.5 km</QUANTITY> and reach the <GPE>LPR</GPE> administrative border,\" he said.With the advance near <GPE>Myasozharovka</GPE>, <NORP>Russian</NORP> troops have also begun to deliver \"more precise fire\" at enemy units stationed in the area of the community of <GPE>Lozovaya</GPE>, he said.<GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <ORG>Defense Ministry</ORG> reported on <DATE>September 29</DATE> that <ORG>Battlegroup West</ORG> units had liberated the settlement of <GPE>Makeyevka</GPE> as a result of successful offensive operations.As <PERSON>Marochko</PERSON> pointed out, the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army controlled <PERCENT>less than 1%</PERCENT> of <GPE>LPR</GPE> territory after <NORP>Russian</NORP> troops liberated <GPE>Makeyevka</GPE>."
"<GPE>MOSCOW</GPE>, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.<GPE>Moscow</GPE> says <GPE>Bern</GPE> is not neutral enough to mediate the <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> conflict; <NORP><GPE>Russia</GPE>n</NORP> Foreign Minister <PERSON>Sergey Lavrov</PERSON> comes to <GPE>Laos</GPE> for the <LOC>Asia</LOC> summit; and <GPE>Russia</GPE>, <GPE>China</GPE> have a cooperative vision for <LOC>Eurasia</LOC>.These stories topped <DATE>Friday</DATE>'s newspaper headlines in <GPE>Russia</GPE>.<GPE>Switzerland</GPE> is not a neutral party in the <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> crisis, so <GPE>Moscow</GPE> believes it cannot serve as a proper mediator in peace talks, <ORG>the Russian Embassy</ORG> in <GPE>Switzerland</GPE> told <ORG>Izvestia</ORG>.\"<GPE>Switzerland</GPE> is <PERCENT>100%</PERCENT> <NORP>pro-Ukrainian</NORP>, joining all of the <ORG>EU</ORG>’s <NORP>anti-Russian</NORP> sanctions.It said goodbye to neutrality a long time ago.And we see no signs that <GPE>Switzerland</GPE> is ready to discuss ways out of the <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> conflict that would take into consideration <GPE>Russia</GPE>’s interests,\" the <GPE>Russia</GPE>n diplomats said.However, the <NORP>Swiss</NORP> <ORG>Foreign Ministry</ORG> emphasized that the <NORP>Central European</NORP> country not only favors involving <GPE>Moscow</GPE> in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> talks but is also working toward that goal.\"Since the very beginning, <GPE>Switzerland</GPE> has stated that peace is possible with <GPE>Russia</GPE> only.We support maintaining dialogue with all sides as we continue working toward integrating <GPE>Russia</GPE> [in the process],\" <ORG>Foreign Ministry</ORG> Spokesman <PERSON>Jonas Montani</PERSON> said in an interview with <ORG>Izvestia</ORG>.\"<GPE>Switzerland</GPE> no longer has the moral right to be called a neutral state.While <GPE>Switzerland</GPE> could potentially regain its neutrality, it has not only become affiliated with the political <LOC>West</LOC> but is also one of its major mouthpieces,\" said <PERSON>Alexander Konkov</PERSON>, associate professor of <ORG>the Financial University</ORG> run by the <NORP>Russian</NORP> government.Even as <GPE>Switzerland</GPE> is not an <ORG>EU</ORG> member, <GPE>Bern</GPE> has supported all sanctions imposed on <GPE>Moscow</GPE> by <GPE>Brussels</GPE>, with <NORP>Swiss</NORP> restrictions currently affecting <CARDINAL>more than 2,200</CARDINAL> individuals, legal entities and businessmen.Also, the <NORP>Swiss</NORP> government has frozen <MONEY>$8.8 bln</MONEY> worth of <NORP><GPE>Russia</GPE>n</NORP> assets since <GPE>Russia</GPE> launched its special military operation.Meanwhile, <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> President <PERSON>Vladimir Zelensky</PERSON> embarked on another <NORP>European</NORP> tour to promote his \"victory plan\" amid <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>’s failures on the battlefield, with the latest being the loss of <GPE>Ugledar</GPE>.He had big hopes for the <PERSON>Ramstein</PERSON> meeting originally scheduled to take place in <GPE>Germany</GPE> on <DATE>October 12</DATE>, but the organizers canceled the meeting without explaining why.On <DATE>Thursday</DATE>, <NORP>Russian</NORP> Foreign Minister <PERSON>Sergey Lavrov</PERSON> arrived in <GPE>Laos</GPE> to attend events hosted by <ORG>the Association of Southeast Asian Nations</ORG> (<ORG>ASEAN</ORG>).This is his <ORDINAL>second</ORDINAL> visit to <GPE>Laos</GPE> <DATE>this year</DATE>.In <DATE>July</DATE>, he attended a meeting of foreign ministers, while this time around, he’s in <GPE>Vientiane</GPE> for higher-level summits.On <DATE>October 11</DATE>, <EVENT>the East Asia Summit</EVENT> will bring together <CARDINAL>18</CARDINAL> partners, including <GPE>Russia</GPE>, <GPE>the United States</GPE>, <ORG>the European Union</ORG>, <GPE>Japan</GPE>, <GPE>Australia</GPE>, <GPE>South Korea</GPE>, <GPE>India</GPE> and <GPE>China</GPE>, among other countries.<PERSON>Lavrov</PERSON> will take part in this event alongside <GPE>US</GPE> Secretary of <ORG>State</ORG> <PERSON>Antony Blinken</PERSON>.The <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> top diplomats have not held bilateral meetings since the launch of the special military operation, nor are they planning to meet on <DATE>Friday</DATE>.<DATE>Today</DATE>’s summit will focus on security issues in <LOC>the</LOC> <LOC>Asia-Pacific</LOC> where, <GPE>Moscow</GPE> says, <LOC>the</LOC> situation has deteriorated amid <ORG>NATO</ORG>’s intentions to militarize <LOC>the</LOC> region.Earlier, <PERSON>Daniel Kritenbrink</PERSON>, <GPE>US</GPE> Assistant Secretary of <ORG>State</ORG> for <NORP>East Asian</NORP> and Pacific Affairs, announced that <GPE>Washington</GPE> plans to discuss human rights in <GPE>Myanmar</GPE>, what he called <GPE>China</GPE>’s reckless behavior in the South <GPE>China</GPE> Sea, where it has had sporadic clashes with <ORG>ASEAN</ORG> member countries over territorial claims, and <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>.Over <DATE>the past year</DATE>, since <GPE>Russia</GPE> has singled out <ORG>ASEAN</ORG> as a priority in its foreign policy doctrine, there has been no breakthrough in relations between <GPE>Russia</GPE> and the <NORP>Southeast Asian</NORP> union - and none was expected, Deputy Director of <ORG>HSE Center for Comprehensive European and International Studies</ORG> <PERSON>Alexander Korolev</PERSON> told <ORG>Vedomosti</ORG>.Rather, he said, <GPE>Russia</GPE> continues to develop relations with individual <ORG>ASEAN</ORG> member countries, primarily <GPE>Malaysia</GPE>, whose Prime Minister <PERSON>Anwar Ibrahim</PERSON> talked cooperation in <NORP>Islamic</NORP> banking at <EVENT>the Eastern Economic Forum</EVENT> in <GPE>Russia</GPE> and has been actively campaigning for his country's membership in <ORG>BRICS</ORG>, as have been <GPE>Vietnam</GPE>, <GPE>Myanmar</GPE> and <GPE>Indonesia</GPE>.According to <PERSON>Korolev</PERSON>, even as <ORG>ASEAN</ORG> has dodged any discussions on <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>, the topic still comes up at these twice yearly events.The talk, however, centers around the <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> conflict’s impact on food and energy security rather than its military and political implications.Therefore, <ORG>ASEAN</ORG> will formally refrain from taking sides with either <GPE>Russia</GPE> or the <LOC>West</LOC>, even as <ORG>ASEAN</ORG> diplomats often signal at informal meetings that they support <GPE>Russia</GPE>, the expert concluded.Developing cooperation between <GPE>Russia</GPE> and <GPE>China</GPE> in <LOC>Eurasia</LOC>, especially in <LOC>Central Asia</LOC>, will help the <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> countries build a more just world order globally that reaps rewards for as many countries from <LOC>the Global South</LOC>, or what <GPE>Moscow</GPE> calls the global majority, as possible.At that, the <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> countries should focus on pragmatic aspects and mutual benefits rather than trying to oppose the <LOC>West</LOC> in their work, according to a joint report from <ORG>the Russian International Affairs Council</ORG>, <ORG>the Institute of China and Contemporary Asia</ORG> at <ORG>the Russian Academy of Sciences</ORG> and the <GPE>Shanghai-based</GPE> <ORG>Fudan University</ORG> seen by <ORG>Kommersant</ORG>.The <DATE>annual</DATE> report titled <WORK_OF_ART><GPE>Russia</GPE>n-Chinese Dialogue: The 2024 Model</WORK_OF_ART>, to be released <TIME>later on Friday</TIME> comes as <GPE>Russia</GPE> and <GPE>China</GPE> mark the <ORDINAL>75th</ORDINAL> anniversary of diplomatic relations.Among major conclusions, the report said that <GPE>Moscow</GPE> and <GPE>Beijing</GPE> should work together to develop relations with <LOC>Central Asia</LOC>, a key element of the Greater Eurasian Partnership Concept introduced by <GPE>Russia</GPE> and <GPE>China</GPE>’s <ORG>Belt and Road Initiative</ORG> and the nucleus of <ORG>the Shanghai Cooperation Organization</ORG> (<ORG>SCO</ORG>), to prevent the region from becoming another zone of competition.The joint role <GPE>Moscow</GPE> and <GPE>Beijing</GPE> are playing to develop the <ORG>SCO</ORG> and <ORG>BRICS</ORG> as brand-new international platforms is also key, the authors of the report insist.Both groups have expanded in political terms in <DATE>2024</DATE>, with <ORG>BRICS</ORG> doubling from <CARDINAL>five</CARDINAL> to <CARDINAL>10</CARDINAL> member countries and the <ORG>SCO</ORG>, too, increasing the number of its members to <CARDINAL>10</CARDINAL>.\"<GPE>Russia</GPE> and <GPE>China</GPE> are the driving forces behind <ORG>BRICS</ORG>  for the bulk of substantive initiatives originate from these <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> countries.In addition, <GPE>Russia</GPE> plays a leading role in aligning large players struggling to solve major disputes between themselves politically, such as <GPE>China</GPE> and <GPE>India</GPE> or <GPE>Iran</GPE> and <GPE>Saudi Arabia</GPE>.And <GPE>China</GPE> plays a similar role economically,\" <CARDINAL>one</CARDINAL> of the authors and director of the Institute of <GPE>China</GPE> and Contemporary Asia, <PERSON>Kirill Babayev</PERSON>, told <ORG>Kommersant</ORG>.On <DATE>Thursday</DATE>, <NORP>Russian</NORP> Presidential Aide <PERSON>Yury Ushakov</PERSON> who heads the organizing committee for the next <ORG>BRICS</ORG> summit told reporters that the grouping’s gathering in <GPE>Kazan</GPE> <DATE>later this month</DATE> could \"become the largest foreign policy event ever held in our country.\"So far, <CARDINAL>32</CARDINAL> countries have sent confirmations to attend the summit to which <CARDINAL>as many as 38</CARDINAL> countries, including <ORG>BRICS</ORG> member countries and nations seeking cooperation with the intergovernmental organization have been invited, <PERSON>Ushakov</PERSON> said.All <CARDINAL>ten</CARDINAL> <ORG>BRICS</ORG> member countries have agreed to take part, he added.Also, countries that chair regional integration associations in <LOC>Southeast Asia</LOC>, <LOC>Africa</LOC>, <LOC>Latin America</LOC> and <LOC>the Middle East</LOC> have been invited.The summit will also welcome <ORG>UN</ORG> Secretary-General <PERSON>Antonio Guterres</PERSON>, <ORG>SCO</ORG> Secretary General <PERSON>Zhang Ming</PERSON>, secretaries general from <GPE>the Commonwealth of Independent States</GPE>, the <ORG>EAEU</ORG>, <GPE>the Union State</GPE> as well as President of <ORG>the BRICS New Development Bank</ORG> <PERSON>Dilma Rousseff</PERSON>.The <ORDINAL>16th</ORDINAL> <ORG>BRICS</ORG> summit will be the <ORDINAL>first</ORDINAL> held since the group’s <CARDINAL>five</CARDINAL> founding members <GPE>Russia</GPE>, <GPE>China</GPE>, <GPE>Brazil</GPE>, <GPE>India</GPE> and <GPE>South Africa</GPE> were joined by <GPE>Egypt</GPE>, <GPE>Ethiopia</GPE>, <GPE>Iran</GPE>, the <GPE>UAE</GPE> and <GPE>Saudi Arabia</GPE> <DATE>early this year</DATE>.As the original members of <ORG>BRICS</ORG> decided to expand at <DATE>last year’s</DATE> summit in <GPE>South Africa</GPE>, there are limited opportunities to accept more members, <PERSON>Yaroslav Lisovolik</PERSON>, founder of the <ORG>BRICS</ORG>+ Analytics company, said, as additional criteria and conditions for further expansion need to be formulated.However, there are <CARDINAL>tens</CARDINAL> of countries who would like to work with <ORG>BRICS</ORG>, the expert added.\"This is why the idea to establish a ‘belt of friends’ looks justified,\" <PERSON>Lisovolik</PERSON> told <ORG>Vedomosti</ORG>.The expert pointed to the growing interest in settlements in national currencies among <ORG>BRICS</ORG>.Additional payment systems could meet the rising demand for transactions between them.Merging the digital currency platforms of central banks from <ORG>BRICS</ORG> countries and their partners is the most interesting idea, he said.Multiple ideas and proposals have been announced ahead of the summit in <GPE>Kazan</GPE>, <PERSON>Denis Denisov</PERSON>, an expert at <ORG>the Financial University</ORG> run by the <NORP>Russian</NORP> government, said.These include setting up an alternative to <ORG>SWIFT</ORG> not only for the sake of financial diversification but also amid the West’s ability to impose sanctions on economies that it does not like within <TIME>hours</TIME>, the expert explained.<GPE>Russia</GPE> expects that foreign companies will largely cease to exit its market as it included a substantial decrease in revenues from gratuitous payments into its draft budget for <DATE>the next three years</DATE>, including those from the sale of assets of foreign owners, to a symbolic <MONEY>300 mln rubles</MONEY> ($<MONEY>3 mln</MONEY>) <DATE>annually</DATE> from <MONEY>141 bln rubles</MONEY> ($<MONEY>1.45 bln</MONEY>) that the authority expects to receive <DATE>this year</DATE>, <ORG>Izvestia</ORG> has learned.As the government has lowered expectations for gratuitous revenues in <DATE>2025-2027</DATE>, it obviously does not pencil in any major exit of foreigners, <PERSON>Natalya Milchakova</PERSON>, a lead analyst at <ORG>Freedom Finance Global</ORG>, argues.\"The majority of foreign owners who wanted to leave <GPE>Russia</GPE> have already done so - or will do so before <DATE>the end of 2024</DATE> - by paying a <PERCENT>15%</PERCENT> fee.So, the government has perhaps achieved its goal - to let politically neutral foreign companies stay, especially when it comes to large market players,\" she said.Over <DATE>the past two years</DATE>, <ORG>McDonald's</ORG>, <ORG>Shell</ORG>, <ORG>Siemens</ORG>, <ORG>Nissan</ORG>, <ORG>IKEA</ORG> and other large global businesses have departed from <GPE>Russia</GPE>.In <DATE>2024</DATE> alone, <ORG>Danone</ORG>, <ORG>Hewlett-Packard</ORG> (<ORG>HP</ORG>), <ORG>Hyundai</ORG> and <GPE>Britain</GPE>’s <ORG>Unilever</ORG> have closed up shop in <GPE>Russia</GPE>, while <ORG>Philip Morris</ORG>, <ORG>Auchan</ORG> and <ORG>Metro</ORG> still stay.Gratuitous revenues are <CARDINAL>one</CARDINAL> of the <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> major groups of budget revenues, with the other <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> being tax and non-tax revenues, <PERSON>Vladimir Klimanov</PERSON> from <ORG>the Presidential Academy</ORG> explained.However, these revenues are not critical for <GPE>Russia</GPE>’s coffers, he said.According to <PERSON>Milchakova</PERSON>, they accounted for a mere <PERCENT>2%</PERCENT> of all budget revenues or <PERCENT>0.6%</PERCENT> of GDP <DATE>this year</DATE>, and <DATE>next year</DATE> they will amount to <PERCENT>less than 1%</PERCENT>, given the current draft budget.<ORG>TASS</ORG> is not responsible for the material quoted in these press reviews"
"<GPE>BELGOROD</GPE>, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.<GPE>Ukraine</GPE> has fired <CARDINAL>46</CARDINAL> unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs), which is almost twice more than <DATE>yesterday</DATE>, and <CARDINAL><CARDINAL>9</CARDINAL>6</CARDINAL> munitions at <CARDINAL>9</CARDINAL> districts in <GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <GPE>Belgorod Region</GPE> over <DATE>the past day</DATE>, injuring <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> people, the region’s governor, <PERSON>Vyacheslav Gladkov</PERSON>, said on his Telegram channel.\"In the <NORP>Shebekinsky</NORP> district, <CARDINAL>1<CARDINAL>2</CARDINAL></CARDINAL> munitions in <CARDINAL>2</CARDINAL> shelling rounds and <CARDINAL>five</CARDINAL> <PRODUCT>UAVs</PRODUCT> were fired at the city of <GPE>Shebekino</GPE>, the villages of <GPE>Dobroye</GPE>, <GPE>Murom</GPE>, <GPE>Rzhevka</GPE>.<CARDINAL>Two</CARDINAL> civilians were wounded.<CARDINAL>27</CARDINAL> flats in <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> apartment buildings, <CARDINAL>eight</CARDINAL> private houses, <CARDINAL>80</CARDINAL> passenger cars, <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> outbuildings, an administrative building, a room in an agricultural facility and an industrial production facility were damaged,\" he wrote.The <GPE>Borisovsky</GPE> district was attacked by <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> UAVs, <CARDINAL>one</CARDINAL> civilian was injured as a result of the attack.A total of <CARDINAL>39</CARDINAL> munitions and <CARDINAL>16</CARDINAL> drones were fired at the <GPE>Belgorod</GPE> district, damaging <CARDINAL>5</CARDINAL> private houses, <CARDINAL>nine</CARDINAL> passenger cars and <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> outbuildings.<CARDINAL>Ten</CARDINAL> munitions and a drone were fired at the settlements in the <GPE>Volokonovsky</GPE> district.A social facility, a public transport stop and a power supply line were damaged.The <LOC>Grayvoronsky</LOC> district was attacked by <CARDINAL>21</CARDINAL> munitions and <CARDINAL>11</CARDINAL> UAVs.<CARDINAL>Fouteen</CARDINAL> munitions and <CARDINAL>five</CARDINAL> drones were fired at the <GPE>Krasnoyaruzhsky</GPE> district.<CARDINAL>One</CARDINAL> administrative building was damaged.<CARDINAL>Five</CARDINAL> aerial targets were destroyed by an air defense system in the skies over the <GPE>Prokhorovsky</GPE>, <GPE>Starooskolsky</GPE> and <GPE>Yakovlevsky</GPE> districts, <CARDINAL>four</CARDINAL> passenger cars were damaged."
"<GPE>MOSCOW</GPE>, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.Teams of <ORG>the Russian Defense Ministry’s</ORG> new <FAC>Rubicon Center</FAC> <ORG>of Advanced Unmanned Technologies</ORG> are operating in the <GPE>Donetsk</GPE>, <GPE>Belgorod</GPE> and <GPE>Kursk</GPE> directions of the special military operation, the ministry reported on <DATE>Friday</DATE>.<GPE>Russia</GPE>’s <ORG>Defense</ORG> Minister <PERSON>Andrey Belousov</PERSON> inspected the work of the new center and held a meeting on developing unmanned technologies in the <GPE>Russia</GPE>n Armed Forces on <DATE>October 11</DATE>, the ministry specified.\"<PERSON>Andrey Belousov</PERSON> listened to a report on the work of the <FAC>Center</FAC>’s teams in the area of the special military operation, in particular, in the <GPE>Donetsk</GPE>, <GPE>Belgorod</GPE> and <GPE>Kursk</GPE> directions.The <ORG>Center</ORG>’s teams have destroyed <CARDINAL>more than 400</CARDINAL> items of armament and equipment of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army and wiped out <CARDINAL>about 800</CARDINAL> site targets,\" the ministry said in a statement.\"UAV teams outfitted with control devices with artificial intelligence elements carry out combat operations round-the-clock.The targets uncovered by reconnaissance drones are promptly transmitted to control posts for using attack UAVs,\" it said.The <FAC>Center</FAC>’s combat units are staffed with engineers, technicians, communications and logistics support specialists, military medics, reconnaissance and analytical groups to accomplish combat objectives highly efficiently, it specified.\"The defense minister viewed the work of the <ORG>Center</ORG>’s operators at an UAV control post.He also inspected an analytical group assigned with generalizing information on the use of systems and capabilities, analyzing statistics on reported video materials and elaborating proposals on increasing the efficiency of applying technology.The combat experience gained is used to train operators of unmanned aerial vehicles and other robotic systems,\" the ministry said."
"<PERSON>VIENTIANE</PERSON> /<GPE>Laos</GPE>/, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.<GPE>Russia</GPE> is aware of various political statements calling for a settlement in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>, but so far, it has not found anything serious in them, <GPE>Russia</GPE>n Foreign Minister <PERSON>Sergey Lavrov</PERSON> stated during a press conference.\"Every day, new statements emerge - [<NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> President <PERSON>Vladimir] Zelensky</PERSON> says <CARDINAL>one</CARDINAL> thing <DATE>today</DATE>, something different <DATE>tomorrow</DATE>, and then his administration, or what they call the Office of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> President, corrects him,\" <PERSON>Lavrov</PERSON> pointed out.\"It is pointless to follow this.What truly matters are the actions on the ground and the practical steps taken by politicians when something serious is proposed.So far, we see our armed forces consistently achieving their objectives on the ground, and we have not found anything serious in the statements of politicians yet,\" he added.<GPE>Kiev</GPE> has repeatedly rejected peace and mediation initiatives from <ORDINAL>third</ORDINAL> countries, saying it will only promote the so-called <PERSON>Zelensky</PERSON> formula.In <DATE>late September</DATE>, before leaving for <GPE>the United States</GPE>, <PERSON>Zelensky</PERSON> said he had some kind of \"plan\" to increase pressure on <GPE>Russia</GPE>, which he would first show to <GPE>US</GPE> leader <PERSON>Joe Biden</PERSON>.Later, <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> <ORG>Presidential Office</ORG> Head <PERSON>Andrey Yermak</PERSON> clarified that the \"plan\" would be shown to the country’s citizens only after it had been presented to <GPE>Kiev</GPE>’s <NORP>Western</NORP> partners, while certain sensitive elements would remain closed to the country’s population.On <DATE>June 14</DATE>, <NORP>Russian</NORP> President <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> at a meeting with <ORG>the Foreign Ministry</ORG> set out the country’s conditions for settling the situation in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>.Among them are the withdrawal of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> armed forces from <GPE>Donbass</GPE> and <GPE>Novorossiya</GPE> and <GPE>Kiev</GPE>’s refusal to join <ORG>NATO</ORG>.In addition, <GPE>Russia</GPE> wants all <NORP>Western</NORP> sanctions against it lifted and demands that <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> commit to a non-aligned and nuclear-free status.<PERSON>Putin</PERSON> indicated that if <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> and the <LOC>West</LOC> refuse these conditions, they could change in the future.<GPE>Kiev</GPE> rejected the <NORP>Russian</NORP> peace plan.After <LOC>the</LOC> massive <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> attack on <LOC>the</LOC> <GPE>Kursk Region</GPE> that began on <DATE>August 6</DATE>, <LOC>the</LOC> <NORP>Russian</NORP> leader said that negotiations with a government that attacks civilians are pointless."
"<PERSON>VIENTIANE</PERSON> /<GPE>Laos</GPE>/, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.The <NORP>Russian</NORP> side is not interested in <GPE>Kiev</GPE>’s information about possible settlement conferences, <GPE>Moscow</GPE>'s position has already been clearly voiced by <NORP>Russian</NORP> President <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON>, Foreign Minister <PERSON>Sergey Lavrov</PERSON> said at a press conference following his participation in the <ORDINAL>19th</ORDINAL> <EVENT>East Asia Summit</EVENT>.\"I do not follow the information regularly expressed by <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> representatives at various levels.We are not interested in it,\" the top diplomat said, commenting on <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> Ambassador to <GPE>Turkey</GPE> <PERSON>Vasily Bodnar</PERSON>'s statement that <GPE>Kiev</GPE> continues to work on organizing a <ORDINAL>second</ORDINAL> so-called peace summit before <DATE>the end of this year</DATE>.<PERSON>Lavrov</PERSON> pointed out that <GPE>Moscow</GPE>'s position was \"extremely clearly stated by the <NORP>Russian</NORP> president at <ORG>the Foreign Ministry</ORG> on <DATE>June 14</DATE>.\"\"This position is being consistently put into practice, and we will bring the matter to an end,\" the <NORP>Russian</NORP> foreign minister added.The <ORDINAL>first</ORDINAL> conference on <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> was held on <DATE>June 15-16</DATE> in the <NORP>Swiss</NORP> city of <GPE>Burgenstock</GPE> at the initiative of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> side.<GPE>Russia</GPE> was not invited to take part in the event.Delegations of some states, including <GPE>China</GPE>, did not participate in the forum.None of the <ORG>BRICS</ORG> member states supported the final communique.<ORG>Russian Foreign Ministry</ORG> Spokeswoman <PERSON>Maria Zakharova</PERSON> emphasized that the conference was a complete fiasco, saying that \"such gatherings cannot serve as a basis for sustainable peace.\"On <DATE>June 14</DATE>, <NORP>Russian</NORP> President <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> at a meeting with <ORG>the Foreign Ministry</ORG> set out the country’s conditions for settling the situation in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>.Among them are the withdrawal of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> armed forces from <GPE>Donbass</GPE> and <GPE>Novorossiya</GPE> and <GPE>Kiev</GPE>'s refusal to join <ORG>NATO</ORG>.In addition, <GPE>Russia</GPE> wants all <NORP>Western</NORP> sanctions against it lifted and demands that <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> commit to a non-aligned and nuclear-free status.<PERSON>Putin</PERSON> indicated that if <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> and the <LOC>West</LOC> refuse these conditions, they could change in the future.<GPE>Kiev</GPE> rejected the <NORP>Russian</NORP> peace plan.After the massive <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> attack on <GPE>the Kursk Region</GPE> that began on <DATE>August 6</DATE>, the <NORP>Russian</NORP> leader said that negotiations with a government that attacks civilians are pointless."
"<GPE>KURSK</GPE>, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.<NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> armed forces have deliberately destroyed a civilian hospital in the <GPE>Sudzha</GPE> district by artillery at the start of the incursion into the border area of <GPE>the Kursk Region</GPE>, a local resident told a military investigator of <ORG>the Russian Investigative Committee</ORG>, <ORG>TASS</ORG> has a video of his testimony at its disposal.\"And on <DATE>the same day</DATE>, by <TIME>lunchtime</TIME>, they started shelling the hospital.It was an artillery strike.They (the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> armed forces - <ORG>TASS</ORG>) were bombing so heavily, very intensely, there was severe shelling.No one even tried counting the attacks, we were already down [in the shelter],\" the man said.According to him, there were many damaged houses and civilian vehicles in the settlements he passed through.The local noted that the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> military did not even intend to target <NORP>Russian</NORP> troops, and it was only civilian infrastructure and local residents who were hit."
"<PERSON>VIENTIANE</PERSON>/<GPE>Laos</GPE>, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.The final declaration of the <ORDINAL>19th</ORDINAL> <EVENT>East Asia Summit</EVENT> (<ORG>EAS</ORG>) could not be adopted due to persistent attempts by <GPE>the United States</GPE> and a number of other countries to shift the focus of the document to controversial geopolitical issues, <NORP>Russian</NORP> Foreign Minister <PERSON>Sergey Lavrov</PERSON> said at a press conference following his attending the summit.\"The final declaration could not be adopted due to persistent attempts by <GPE>the United States</GPE>, <GPE>Japan</GPE>, <GPE>South Korea</GPE>, <GPE>Australia</GPE>, <GPE>New Zealand</GPE> to politicize this document, to depart from the policy that has been applied at <EVENT>the East Asia Summits</EVENT> for <DATE>many decades</DATE>, namely, to prevent saturating the declarations with geopolitical confrontational subjects,\" the <NORP>Russian</NORP> top diplomat said.<PERSON>Lavrov</PERSON> noted that in <DATE>recent years</DATE>, the declarations have laid out practical cooperation in economy, trade, investments, and the humanitarian sphere.\"The fact that attempts to saturate these work programs [with politicized subjects] are, needless to say, counterproductive, is obvious to everyone,\" he stated.\"<DATE>Last year</DATE> we adopted an action plan for <EVENT>the East Asia Summits</EVENT>.And during the current event, we made a variety of practical considerations that are aimed at implementing projects in the areas outlined in this joint plan,\" <PERSON>Lavrov</PERSON> emphasized.\"The <LOC>West</LOC> has been methodically blocking all these efforts, demanding in turn that we take all responsibility for what is happening in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>, where the <GPE>US</GPE> and its allies instigated a coup and have supported the actions of the criminal <GPE>Kiev</GPE> regime ever since.\"\"That is probably the main reason.<ORG>ASEAN</ORG> countries are well aware that this does not contribute to the development of cooperation in the format of <EVENT>the East Asia Summits</EVENT>,\" the <NORP>Russian</NORP> foreign minister concluded."
"<GPE>MOSCOW</GPE>, <DATE>October 11</DATE>.The <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> armed forces are demoralized and rout when facing <NORP>Russian</NORP> troops advancing towards <GPE>Krasnoarmeysk</GPE> (<GPE>Pokrovsk</GPE>) on the <GPE>Avdeyevka</GPE> direction, according to commander of the <ORG>Battlegroup Center</ORG> deep reconnaissance squad, call sign '<PERSON>Yurist</PERSON>'.\"Our enemies, the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> armed forces, are fleeing.They are demoralized and try to rout without looking back at the first fire contact.Actually, we slowly, but steadily, approach the city of <GPE>Pokrovsk</GPE>, the enemy’s major logistical node,\" he said on a video, published by <ORG>the Russian Defense Ministry</ORG>."
"<GPE>WASHINGTON</GPE>, <DATE>October 10</DATE>.<ORG>The World Bank's</ORG> executive board has approved the creation of a new fund to support <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>, <ORG>Reuters</ORG> reported, citing sources.According to the news agency, it is expected that <GPE>the United States</GPE>, <GPE>Canada</GPE> and <GPE>Japan</GPE> will contribute funds.<ORG>Reuters</ORG> emphasized that the <NORP>Russian</NORP> side voted against the creation of the fund.<ORG>The World Bank’s</ORG> press service has not yet commented on this information.Executive Director of <ORG>the World Bank</ORG> representing <GPE>Russia</GPE> <PERSON>Roman Marshavin</PERSON> told <ORG>TASS</ORG> in an interview in <DATE>July</DATE> that the bank's experts openly warned about <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>'s insolvency and its problems with corruption.According to him, if <GPE>Kiev</GPE> defaults, its debts to this financial organization will have to be paid by other countries."
"<GPE>MOSCOW</GPE>, <DATE>October 10</DATE>.The <ORDINAL>second</ORDINAL> peace conference on the settlement of the conflict in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> will be held in <DATE>November</DATE>, <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> President <PERSON>Vladimir Zelensky</PERSON> said, contradicting his office's statements from <DATE>the previous day</DATE>.\"The next 'peace summit' should be held in <DATE>November</DATE>, the plan will be on the table.I don't know the date [of its holding].Nobody knows [the date] now, but we will prepare everything,\" he told reporters after talks with his <NORP>French</NORP> counterpart <PERSON>Emmanuel Macron</PERSON> in <GPE>Paris</GPE>.On <DATE>Tuesday</DATE>, <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> presidential office adviser <PERSON>Darya Zarovnaya</PERSON> said that the <ORDINAL>second</ORDINAL> conference on the settlement of the conflict in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>, which <GPE>Kiev</GPE> had hoped to hold in <DATE>November this year</DATE>, would not take place.<GPE>Moscow</GPE> has repeatedly criticized the so-called peace formula promoted by <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> as unrealistic, pointing to the need to take into account the realities on the ground.<NORP>Russian</NORP> President <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> listed the conditions for the conflict settlement, among them the withdrawal of <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>'s troops from <GPE>Donbass</GPE> and <GPE>Novorossiya</GPE> and <GPE>Kiev</GPE>'s refusal to join <ORG>NATO</ORG>.In addition, <GPE>Russia</GPE> considers necessary the lifting of all <NORP>Western</NORP> sanctions against it and the establishment of <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>'s non-aligned and nuclear-free status.The <ORDINAL>first</ORDINAL> conference on <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> was held on <DATE>June 15-16</DATE> in the <NORP>Swiss</NORP> city of <GPE>Burgenstock</GPE> at the initiative of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> side.<GPE>Russia</GPE> was not invited to take part in the event.Delegations of some states, including <GPE>China</GPE>, did not participate in the forum.None of the <ORG>BRICS</ORG> member states supported the final communique.<ORG>Russian Foreign Ministry</ORG> Spokeswoman <PERSON>Maria Zakharova</PERSON> emphasized that the conference was a complete fiasco, saying that \"such gatherings cannot serve as a basis for sustainable peace.\"."
"<GPE>MOSCOW</GPE>, <DATE>October 10</DATE>.A large group of <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> servicemen with equipment has fled home across the border with <GPE>the Kursk Region</GPE>, Deputy Chief of <ORG>the Russian Armed Forces’</ORG> <ORG>Main Military-Political Department</ORG>, <ORG>Akhmat Special Forces</ORG> Commander Major General <PERSON>Apty Alaudinov</PERSON> said.\"I would like to note that in our <GPE>Kursk</GPE> area, the fighters of all units are working very well, fighting with dignity.In particular, I would like to praise <ORG>the 155th marine brigade</ORG>.They are the best.I'd like to say that <DATE>today</DATE> we saw that a very large group of enemy vehicles simply ran away from the territory of <LOC>the Kursk Region</LOC>, ran across the border, ran over, let's say, losing some of their tanks, which were burned by the same servicemen of <ORG>the 155th brigade</ORG> on the move,\" <PERSON>Alaudinov</PERSON> during a <ORG>Rossiya-24 TV</ORG> broadcast.He pointed out that he saw everything with his own eyes with the help of a drone.\"I must say that the guys have done a very good job in our area.Over <DATE>the past few days</DATE> we have knocked them (the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> troops - TASS) out of very serious areas.The guys have made good progress,\" the general added.The situation in <GPE>the Kursk Region</GPE> allows to hope optimistically for its early liberation, <PERSON>Alaudinov</PERSON> noted.\"We are moving forward slowly, without hurrying.At this rate, we will probably soon be able to report that <GPE>the Kursk Region</GPE> has been liberated,\" he said.<PERSON>Alaudinov</PERSON> also announced good news about the situation in <GPE>the Kursk Region</GPE> in the near future."
"<GPE>MOSCOW</GPE>, <DATE>October 10</DATE>.Mass defections from <GPE>Kiev</GPE>’s army question the training of <ORG>the 155th Combined Arms Brigade</ORG> of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> ground forces in <GPE>France</GPE>, <NORP>French</NORP> Colonel (Ret.)<PERSON>Peer de Jong</PERSON> told <ORG>TASS</ORG>.Earlier, <NORP>French</NORP> President <PERSON>Emmanuel Macron</PERSON> announced plans to train a <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> brigade equipped with <NORP>French</NORP>-made weapons and hardware.Meanwhile, the <ORG>Le Figaro</ORG> newspaper reports, citing data from the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> <ORG>Prosecutor General’s Office</ORG>, that <CARDINAL>over 15,000</CARDINAL> troops have defected from the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> army since <DATE>the beginning of the year</DATE>.\"President <PERSON>Macron</PERSON> hosted [<NORP>Ukrainian</NORP>] President <PERSON>Zelensky</PERSON> at <FAC>the Elysee Palace</FAC> <DATE>today</DATE>; in the meantime, the situation on the ground is worsening.<GPE>Ukraine</GPE> is backing down in the face of new <NORP><GPE>Russia</GPE>n</NORP> tactics, while <GPE>Russia</GPE> is consistently devouring and digesting <GPE>Kiev</GPE>’s units,\" <PERSON>de Jong</PERSON> said.He described the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> armed forces’ situation as a disaster.According to the expert, the number of <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> defectors, \"which stands at <CARDINAL>5,000</CARDINAL> troops per month,\" is further proof of that.\"These figures call into question efforts to form an up to <CARDINAL>2,000-strong</CARDINAL> <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> brigade in <GPE>France</GPE>,\" he added.<PERSON>De Jong</PERSON> believes that the creation and training of a <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> brigade in <GPE>France</GPE> \"is nothing but mere declarations.\"However, in his words, \"the financial aspect of <GPE>France</GPE>’s support for <GPE>Kiev</GPE> is an exception because <GPE>Paris</GPE> seems to be planning to provide <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> with <MONEY>$3 bln euros</MONEY> in financial aid.\"\"Clearly, it cannot continue like this.The war has been going on for <DATE>almost three years</DATE>,\" <PERSON>de Jong</PERSON> concluded.On <DATE>October 10</DATE>, President <PERSON>Emmanuel Macron</PERSON> of <GPE>France</GPE> and <PERSON>Vladimir Zelensky</PERSON> of <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> held a meeting at <FAC>the Elysee Palace</FAC> in <GPE>Paris</GPE>.Before the meeting, <PERSON>Macron</PERSON> visited a camp where members of a <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> brigade are undergoing training.<GPE>France</GPE> plans to equip the brigade with <CARDINAL>128</CARDINAL> <ORG>VAB</ORG> armored personnel carriers and <CARDINAL>18</CARDINAL> <ORG>Caesar</ORG> self-propelled howitzers."
"<GPE>DUSHANBE</GPE>, <DATE>October 10</DATE>.<GPE>Russia</GPE> does not take part in the so-called peace summits organized by <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> because they are useless, <ORG>Federation Council</ORG> Speaker <PERSON>Valentina Matviyenko</PERSON> told reporters.\"And what is the point of these summits?The <ORDINAL>first</ORDINAL> one failed miserably, the <ORDINAL>second</ORDINAL> one planned by [<NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> President <PERSON>Vladimir] Zelensky</PERSON> would have been just as empty and worthless.It could lead to nothing positive.It is not about peace, it is not about negotiations, it is not about ending the confrontation,\" <PERSON>Matviyenko</PERSON> pointed out.\"We are absolutely not interested in whether there will be a summit or not.We do not take part in such meetings because we do not see any point in them,\" she added.Earlier, <PERSON>Zelensky</PERSON> said that by <DATE>November</DATE> <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> expects to prepare a document to be presented at a new conference on conflict resolution, but did not specify when the conference would be held.Earlier, the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> president's office said it would not be possible to convene it in <DATE>November</DATE>.<GPE>Kiev</GPE> has repeatedly rejected peace and mediation initiatives from <ORDINAL>third</ORDINAL> countries, saying it will only promote the so-called <PERSON>Zelensky</PERSON> formula.In <DATE>late September</DATE>, before leaving for <GPE>the United States</GPE>, <PERSON>Zelensky</PERSON> said he had some kind of \"plan\" to increase pressure on <GPE>Russia</GPE>, which he would first show to <GPE>US</GPE> leader <PERSON>Joe Biden</PERSON>.Later, <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> <ORG>Presidential Office</ORG> Head <PERSON>Andrey Yermak</PERSON> clarified that the \"plan\" would be shown to the country's citizens only after it had been presented to <GPE>Kiev</GPE>'s <NORP>Western</NORP> partners, while certain sensitive elements would remain closed to the country's population.On <DATE>June 14</DATE>, <NORP>Russian</NORP> President <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> at a meeting with <ORG>the Foreign Ministry</ORG> set out the country’s conditions for settling the situation in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>.Among them are the withdrawal of the <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> armed forces from <GPE>Donbass</GPE> and <GPE>Novorossiya</GPE> and <GPE>Kiev</GPE>'s refusal to join <ORG>NATO</ORG>.In addition, <GPE>Russia</GPE> wants all <NORP>Western</NORP> sanctions against it lifted and demands that <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> commit to a non-aligned and nuclear-free status.<PERSON>Putin</PERSON> indicated that if <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> and the <LOC>West</LOC> refuse these conditions, they could change in the future.<GPE>Kiev</GPE> rejected the <NORP>Russian</NORP> peace plan.After the massive <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> attack on <GPE>the Kursk Region</GPE> that began on <DATE>August 6</DATE>, the <NORP>Russian</NORP> leader said that negotiations with a government that attacks civilians are pointless."
"<GPE>WASHINGTON</GPE>, <DATE>October 10</DATE>.<ORG>NATO</ORG> does not rule out the possibility of the <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> conflict going global, said <GPE>United States</GPE> <ORG>Space Force</ORG> Brigadier General <PERSON>Devin Pepper</PERSON>, who is deputy chief of staff for strategic plans and policy at <ORG>NATO</ORG> Supreme Allied Command Transformation.\"Here's <CARDINAL>one</CARDINAL> thing that I think is really a different way of viewing warfare in <ORG>NATO</ORG> than, as opposed to, let's say, the <GPE>US</GPE>.In <ORG>NATO</ORG>, we think of a <NORP>Eurasian</NORP> conflict,\" he said at an event hosted by <ORG>the Mitchell Institute for Aerospace Studies</ORG>.According to <PERSON>Pepper</PERSON>, the bloc has to \"think about the global fight\" even with regard to the <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> conflict.\"That really comes down to that <NORP>Eurasian-centric</NORP> mindset that we have in <ORG>NATO</ORG>, it is not just, you know, focused on a fight with <GPE>Russia</GPE>, but it's focused on a fight that could go global,\" he stressed.<PERSON>Pepper</PERSON> also said that <GPE>Russia</GPE> still posed an existential threat to <ORG>NATO</ORG>, trying to influence its member states, allegedly through election meddling."
"<GPE>LONDON</GPE>, <DATE>October 10</DATE>.<GPE>Britain</GPE>’s Prime Minister <PERSON>Keir Starmer</PERSON> has held talks with <NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> President <PERSON>Vladimir Zelensky</PERSON> in <GPE>London</GPE>, discussing support for <GPE>Kiev</GPE>, the <NORP>British</NORP> government said in a statement.\"The prime minister hosted President <PERSON>Zelensky</PERSON> in <FAC>Downing Street</FAC> <TIME>this morning</TIME> to discuss his victory plan for <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>.The prime minister welcomed the opportunity to be briefed by the president, and underscored the <GPE>UK</GPE>’s steadfast commitment to a sovereign <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>,\" the statement reads.\"Looking ahead to the <DATE>winter</DATE>, and the challenges that would bring, they both agreed on the need to ensure <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> was in the best possible position.The leaders also discussed <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>’s long-term future, and how investment in the country’s security <DATE>today</DATE> would support <LOC>Europe</LOC>’s broader security for generations to come,\" the document notes."
"<GPE>DUSHANBE</GPE>, <DATE>October 10</DATE>.<GPE>Moscow</GPE> does not take part in <GPE>Ukraine-initiated</GPE> \"peace summits\" because they make no sense, <ORG>Federation Council</ORG> (upper house of parliament) Speaker <PERSON>Valentina Matviyenko</PERSON> told reporters.\"What’s the point in these summits?The <ORDINAL>first</ORDINAL> summit failed miserably and the <ORDINAL>second</ORDINAL> one, which [<NORP>Ukrainian</NORP> President <PERSON>Vladimir] Zelensky</PERSON> planned to organize, would have been just as empty and meaningless.It would have had no positive impact.It’s not about peace, talks and an end to the confrontation,\" she pointed out.\"We don’t really care if a summit takes place or not.We don’t take part in these kinds of get-togethers because we see no point in them,\" she added."
"<GPE>TBILISI</GPE>, <DATE>October 10</DATE>.The economic and humanitarian situation in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> is a complete disaster, <NORP>Georgian</NORP> Prime Minister <PERSON>Irakli Kobakhidze</PERSON> said.In <DATE>late September</DATE>, the ruling <ORG><GPE>Georgia</GPE>n Dream - Democratic <GPE>Georgia</GPE></ORG> party released a campaign ad contrasting the footage of destruction caused by military operations in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> to peaceful views of <GPE>Georgia</GPE>.The <GPE>Ukraine-related</GPE> footage is accompanied by a caption saying \"No to war,\" while a caption on the other side of the screen says: \"Choose peace.\"The party also put up posters across the country featuring images from the video.\"Some are nervous because of these posters and the video for only <CARDINAL>one</CARDINAL> reason: for <DATE>two and a half years</DATE>, they have been hiding what is going on in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> from the people, while the economic, humanitarian and infrastructure situation there is a complete disaster,\" <PERSON>Kobakhidze</PERSON> told the <ORG>Imedi TV</ORG> channel.The posters, which were put up in the <NORP>Georgian</NORP> capital of <GPE>Tbilisi</GPE> and other cities, show destroyed homes, bridges, schools, churches and other buildings in <GPE>Artyomovsk</GPE> (called <GPE>Bakhmut</GPE> in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>), <GPE>Kharkov</GPE>, <GPE>Chernigov</GPE>, <GPE>Mariupol</GPE>, <GPE>Irpen</GPE> and <GPE>Donetsk</GPE>.The election campaign has drawn criticism both inside the country and abroad."
"<ORG>UNITED NATIONS</ORG>, <DATE>Feb. 17</DATE> (<ORG>Xinhua</ORG>) -- <GPE>China</GPE>'s permanent representative to <ORG>the United Nations</ORG>, <PERSON>Zhang Jun</PERSON>, said on <DATE>Friday</DATE> that <ORG>NATO</ORG> should contribute positively to world peace and stability, instead of merely being a troublemaker.\"We urge <ORG>NATO</ORG> to draw lessons from history, abandon the obsolete <EVENT>Cold War</EVENT> mentality and bloc confrontation, and stop dangerous acts of creating imaginary enemies, destabilizing <LOC>Europe</LOC>, and messing up <LOC>Asia Pacific</LOC>.It should contribute positively to world peace and stability, instead of merely being a troublemaker,\" <PERSON>Zhang</PERSON> told the <ORG>Security Council</ORG> briefing on <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>.\"I would like to point out that <ORG>NATO</ORG>, on the <CARDINAL>one</CARDINAL> hand, claims to remain a regional defensive alliance, while on the other hand, constantly seeks to breach its geographic confines and expand its agenda, stoke division and tensions, create fears and confrontations, and keep strengthening military and security ties with <LOC>Asia Pacific</LOC> countries,\" said the ambassador.\"This is obviously self-contradictory.We note with concern that the <ORG>NATO</ORG> secretary general recently made many irresponsible and unfounded remarks on the situation of <LOC>Asia Pacific</LOC>,\" <PERSON>Zhang</PERSON> explained.The envoy stressed that the <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> crisis is, in essence, the culmination of security conflicts in <LOC>Europe</LOC> closely related to <ORG>NATO</ORG>'s constant eastern expansion since <EVENT>the Cold War</EVENT>.\"Pursuing absolute security and political exclusion and containment by force against a specific party is the very crux of the reason why <LOC>Europe</LOC> is in the security plight.If following such a mindset, <LOC>Europe</LOC>, and even the whole world will be caught up in greater turmoil,\" he said.\"We once again call on <GPE>Russia</GPE> and <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> to cease fire and start peace negotiations as soon as possible,\" said <PERSON>Zhang</PERSON>.He called on <GPE>the United States</GPE>, <ORG>EU</ORG>, and <ORG>NATO</ORG> to sit down with <GPE>Russia</GPE> for a comprehensive and in-depth dialogue.\"Based on the principle of security indivisibility, they should discuss how to build a balanced, effective, and sustainable security architecture and realize common security,\" he said.\"In this context, every effort should be made to stop any attempt to hype up the conflict and to avoid its escalation and expansion,\" the envoy added.<PERSON>Zhang</PERSON> underscored the importance of strictly complying with international treaties and the implementation of legal obligations in good faith, noting that they are the basic requirements of the rule of law.\"This is what practicing true multilateralism is about.Regrettably, when it comes to negotiated agreements that failed to be implemented, <LAW>the Minsk Agreement</LAW> is not the only case.<LAW>The Paris Agreement</LAW> on climate change faces major setbacks because of the withdrawal of <CARDINAL>one</CARDINAL> key party,\" he said.The <ORG>JCPOA</ORG>, or the <GPE>Iran</GPE> nuclear deal, has yet to be revived, he said.\"Some major bilateral and multilateral treaties and agreements are now being withdrawn from, violated, hollowed out, and weakened.\"\"Should such a trend continue, great harm would be inflicted on the world.This is something we should be highly vigilant against.Relevant countries also should conduct serious reviews and reflections on this,\" said <PERSON>Zhang</PERSON>.The ambassador said that the human society is facing unprecedented challenges, but peace development, cooperation, and mutual benefit are still an unstoppable historical trend.\"Globalization is making our global village smaller, but the world is big enough to accommodate common development and progress of all countries.To strive for a bright future for humankind, all countries should pursue a just cause for common good, and promote inclusiveness, mutual learning, peaceful coexistence, and cooperation,\" the ambassador noted.\"There is a need to respect each other's legitimate and reasonable security concerns, rather than cling to the <EVENT>Cold War</EVENT> mentality or engaging in bloc politics or exclusive small circles,\" he said.\"There is also a need to realize win-win cooperation by integrating to economic globalization, rather than expecting others to lose or trying to stay ahead by suppressing the development of other countries,\" he said.<PERSON>Zhang</PERSON> said that major country should behave in a way commensurate with its status, and work together with others to maintain stable international relations, rather than putting the interests of their own over the common interests of the international community or seeking dominance and dictating the whole world.\"The world is once again at a historical crossroads.We call on all peace-loving countries to unite under the banner of the <ORG>UN</ORG>, practice true multilateralism, and promote the spirit of the rule of law, so as to maintain common security, promote common development, and create a shared future,\" <PERSON>Zhang</PERSON> concluded."
"<GPE>BEIJING</GPE>, <DATE>Feb. 4</DATE> (<ORG>Xinhua</ORG>) -- \"A strong buttress to the blue flag (of the <ORG>UN</ORG>)\" was how <PERSON>Csaba Korosi</PERSON>, president of the <ORDINAL>77th</ORDINAL> session of the <ORG>UN</ORG> General Assembly (<ORG>UN</ORG>GA), depicted <GPE>China</GPE> in <DATE>late September last year</DATE>.The <ORG>UN</ORG> official, who took the occasion of the <ORDINAL>73rd</ORDINAL> anniversary of the founding of <GPE>the People's Republic of <GPE>China</GPE></GPE> back then to acknowledge the country's contribution to promoting development and prosperity, gave credit to <GPE>China</GPE>'s strong support of <ORG>the United Nations</ORG> <CARDINAL>one</CARDINAL> more time on <DATE>Thursday</DATE>.<GPE>China</GPE> is an important partner of <ORG>the United Nations</ORG>, <PERSON>Korosi</PERSON> said as he is visiting the country from <DATE>Wednesday to Saturday</DATE> at the invitation of <NORP>Chinese</NORP> Foreign Minister <PERSON>Qin Gang</PERSON>.There are good reasons for <PERSON>Korosi</PERSON>'s comments.<GPE>China</GPE>, a permanent member of <ORG>the UN Security Council</ORG> and the <ORDINAL>first</ORDINAL> country to put its signature on <LAW>the UN Charter</LAW>, has been firmly supporting the <ORG>UN-centered</ORG> international system and the international order underpinned by international law, and helping build a more peaceful and better world with its wisdom and solutions.KEY FORCE FOR WORLD PEACE Founded at the end of <EVENT>World War II</EVENT>, <ORG>the United Nations</ORG> bears the expectation of all for permanent peace.Sharing its vision of maintaining peace and stability, <GPE>China</GPE> believes that peace is the most precious, and has practiced \"harmony without uniformity\" since antiquity.Since the founding of <ORG>the United Nations</ORG>, <GPE>China</GPE> has actively participated in the political settlement of major regional hotspot issues, including the <LOC>Korean Peninsula</LOC> nuclear issue, the <GPE>Iran</GPE> nuclear issue, <GPE>Afghanistan</GPE>, <GPE>Myanmar</GPE>, and the <GPE>Palestine-Israel</GPE> issue.It has been upholding the authority and unity of <ORG>the <ORG>UN</ORG> Security Council</ORG>, and supporting <ORG>UN</ORG> mediation in accordance with its mandate.It has also played an active role in the international arms control and disarmament process, and has acceded to <CARDINAL>dozens</CARDINAL> of international arms control treaties and mechanisms, including <LAW>the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons</LAW>.In response to mounting conflicts and security challenges in <DATE>today</DATE>'s world, <NORP>Chinese</NORP> President <PERSON>Xi Jinping</PERSON> proposed the Global Security Initiative (<ORG>GSI</ORG>) at the opening ceremony of <EVENT>the Boao Forum for Asia Annual Conference</EVENT> <DATE>2022</DATE>.The <ORG>GSI</ORG> has won wide recognition from the international community, including <ORG>the United Nations</ORG>.The initiative advocates that humanity is an indivisible security community.It offers <NORP>Chinese</NORP> wisdom to bridge the peace deficit of mankind, and contributes <NORP>Chinese</NORP> solutions to address global security challenges.Regarding the ongoing <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> crisis, <GPE>China</GPE> decides its position and policy based on the merits of the matter concerned, upholds objectivity and fairness, and actively promotes peace talks.\"<GPE>China</GPE>'s idea of being a builder of world peace, contributor to global development, defender of the international order and provider of public goods are consistent with the ideals of <LAW>the <ORG>UN</ORG> Charter</LAW>,\" former <ORG>UN</ORG> Secretary-General <PERSON>Ban Ki-moon</PERSON> has said.ENGINE OF GLOBAL GROWTH \"Facing the severe shocks of <EVENT>COVID-19</EVENT>, we need to work together to steer global development toward a new stage of balanced, coordinated and inclusive growth.To this end, I would like to propose a Global Development Initiative (GDI),\" <PERSON>Xi</PERSON> put forward this idea for the <ORDINAL>first</ORDINAL> time at the general debate of the <ORDINAL>76th</ORDINAL> session of the <ORG>UNGA</ORG> in <DATE>September 2021</DATE>.The initiative aims to stay committed to development as a priority, to a people-centered approach, to benefits for all, to innovation-driven development, to harmony between man and nature and to results-oriented actions.The <ORG>GDI</ORG> has yielded preliminary results.To date, <CARDINAL>more than 100</CARDINAL> countries and a number of international organizations, including <ORG>the United Nations</ORG>, have committed support to the <ORG>GDI</ORG>, and <CARDINAL>close to 70</CARDINAL> countries have joined the Group of Friends of the <ORG>GDI</ORG>.<ORG>A Global Development Promotion Center</ORG> was created, with <CARDINAL>31</CARDINAL> countries and regional organizations joining its network.<ORG>A Global Development Project Pool</ORG> was set up, with the <ORDINAL>first</ORDINAL> list of <CARDINAL>50</CARDINAL> projects launched.A total of <CARDINAL>1,000</CARDINAL> human resources training programs have been conducted, including <CARDINAL>more than 50</CARDINAL> member countries of <ORG>the Group of Friends of the GDI</ORG>.Meanwhile, <ORG>the Belt and Road Initiative</ORG> (<ORG>BRI</ORG>) has become a popular international platform to promote the public good and cooperation since it was proposed <DATE>10 years ago</DATE>, covering <CARDINAL>two <CARDINAL>third</CARDINAL>s</CARDINAL> of countries and a <CARDINAL>third</CARDINAL> of international organizations in the world.<GPE>China</GPE>'s development and contributions will benefit many countries as the world's population exceeds <CARDINAL>8 billion</CARDINAL>, said <PERSON>Natalia Kanem</PERSON>, executive director of <ORG>the UN Population Fund</ORG>.MAKING THE WORLD LESS POOR \"<GPE>China</GPE> has met the basic living needs of its <CARDINAL>1.3 billion-plus</CARDINAL> people and lifted <CARDINAL>over 700 million</CARDINAL> people out of poverty, which is a significant contribution to the global cause of human rights,\" said <PERSON>Xi</PERSON> in his keynote speech at <FAC>the UN Office</FAC> at <GPE>Geneva</GPE> in <DATE>January 2017</DATE>.In <DATE>December 2020</DATE>, <GPE>China</GPE> announced that it has accomplished its poverty alleviation target of <DATE>the new era</DATE> as scheduled.During <DATE>eight years</DATE> of sustained work, <GPE>China</GPE> has lifted its entire rural poor population under the current standard out of poverty.Poverty is a chronical problem in human society.<GPE>China</GPE> is ready to share its experiences with the rest of the world for the global cause of poverty alleviation.In <DATE>recent years</DATE>, <GPE>China</GPE> has supported the development of developing countries through \"<CARDINAL>six <CARDINAL>100</CARDINAL></CARDINAL> projects\" -- <CARDINAL>100</CARDINAL> poverty reduction projects, <CARDINAL>100</CARDINAL> agricultural cooperation projects, <CARDINAL>100</CARDINAL> aid for trade projects, <CARDINAL>100</CARDINAL> ecological conservation and climate change response projects, <CARDINAL>100</CARDINAL> hospitals and clinics, and <CARDINAL>100</CARDINAL> schools and vocational training centers.In <LOC>Asia</LOC>, <GPE>China</GPE> carried out the East <LOC>Asia</LOC> Poverty Reduction Demonstration Cooperation Technical Assistance Projects program in the rural communities of <GPE>Laos</GPE>, <GPE>Cambodia</GPE> and <GPE>Myanmar</GPE>.In <LOC>Africa</LOC>, <GPE>China</GPE> has helped <LOC>Africa</LOC>n countries build water conservancy infrastructure, set up demonstration zones for agricultural cooperation, and carried out <GPE>China</GPE>-<LOC>Africa</LOC> cooperation projects involving a <NORP>Chinese-invented</NORP> technology using grass to grow mushrooms.In the <LOC>South Pacific</LOC> region, <GPE>China</GPE> has carried out technical cooperation assistance projects in infrastructure construction, agriculture and medical care.In <LOC>Latin America</LOC>, <GPE>China</GPE> has built agricultural technology demonstration centers to help local people in recipient countries shake off poverty.Commenting on <GPE>China</GPE>'s poverty reduction drive, <ORG>UN</ORG> Secretary-General <PERSON>Antonio Guterres</PERSON> said those achievements are \"the biggest contribution for dramatical reduction of poverty.\"FIGHTING COVID TOGETHER \"People of different countries have come together.With courage, resolve and compassion which lit the dark hour, we have confronted the disaster head on.The virus will be defeated.Humanity will win this battle,\" <PERSON>Xi</PERSON> said in a statement at the general debate of the <ORDINAL>75th</ORDINAL> session of the <ORG>UNGA</ORG> in <DATE>September 2020</DATE>, when the world was ravaged by the COVID-19 pandemic.Since the outbreak of COVID-19, <GPE>China</GPE> has been sharing with the world its experience in fighting against the virus in a timely manner, assisting other countries with much-needed supplies, and actively engaging in global anti-pandemic cooperation.So far, it has provided anti-pandemic supplies to <CARDINAL><CARDINAL>15</CARDINAL>3</CARDINAL> countries and <CARDINAL>15</CARDINAL> international organizations, and co-hosted <CARDINAL>more than 300</CARDINAL> exchange activities on epidemic prevention and control and medical treatment with over <CARDINAL>180</CARDINAL> countries and regions and <CARDINAL>more than 10</CARDINAL> international organizations.<GPE>China</GPE> is also the <ORDINAL>first</ORDINAL> country to propose COVID-19 vaccines as a global public good, support vaccine intellectual property rights exemption, and champion cooperation on vaccine production with developing countries, which has injected strong impetus into bridging the global immunization gap.Applying Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM) for the treatment of COVID-19 infections, the country has introduced TCM techniques to more than <CARDINAL>150</CARDINAL> countries and regions, and offered ready-for-use TCM to those in need.Lauding <GPE>China</GPE>'s help for developing countries in their fight against the pandemic, <PERSON>Romina Sudack</PERSON>, a member of the Study Group on <GPE>China</GPE> and Argentina of <ORG>the National University of Rosario</ORG>, said <GPE>China</GPE> has been implementing the vision of a community with a shared future for mankind with concrete actions.CHAMPION OF GLOBAL CLIMATE GOVERNANCE Championing the vision of ecological conservation, <GPE>China</GPE> has become a solid contributor to tackling climate change and the betterment of global climate governance.And the <NORP>Chinese</NORP> president has on multiple occasions elaborated on <GPE>China</GPE>'s propositions on jointly building a clean and beautiful world for all countries.\"Clear waters and green mountains are as good as mountains of gold and silver.We must maintain harmony between man and nature and pursue sustainable development,\" <PERSON>Xi</PERSON> said at <FAC>the UN Office</FAC> at <GPE>Geneva</GPE> in <DATE>2017</DATE>.In <DATE>the past decade</DATE>, <GPE>China</GPE> made historic contributions to the conclusion and quick implementation of <LAW>the Paris Agreement</LAW>, was among the <ORDINAL>first</ORDINAL> to adopt and release the country's <LAW>National Plan on Implementation of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development</LAW>, and implement the obligations under <ORG>the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change</ORG> (<ORG>UNFCCC</ORG>).<GPE>China</GPE> also announced <CARDINAL>1</CARDINAL>+N policies for peaking carbon emissions and achieving carbon neutrality with clear timetables and roadmaps.The country has become a world leading player in renewable energy, and is mounting consistent efforts to tap the potential of a green <ORG>BRI</ORG>.As the largest developing country, <GPE>China</GPE> is striving to build a community of life for man and nature with unprecedented ambition and action to help achieve sustainable development worldwide.<ORG>UNFCCC</ORG> Executive Secretary <PERSON>Simon Stiell</PERSON> spoke highly of <GPE>China</GPE>'s firm and consistent stand on actively tackling climate change, as well as its moves to turn climate commitments into concrete actions.At a time when the world is facing an energy crisis, <GPE>China</GPE> continues to make solid progress in dealing with climate change and plays an important role in advancing the global response to climate change, <PERSON>Stiell</PERSON> said."
"<GPE>Japan</GPE>'s National Daily Since <DATE>1922</DATE> <DATE>October 11, <DATE>2024</DATE></DATE> (<GPE>Mainichi</GPE> <GPE>Japan</GPE>)      <GPE>OSLO</GPE> (<GPE>Kyodo</GPE>) - <GPE>Japan</GPE>'s leading organization of atomic bomb survivors, <ORG>Nihon Hidankyo</ORG>, won the <DATE>2024</DATE> <WORK_OF_ART>Nobel Peace Prize</WORK_OF_ART> on <DATE>Friday</DATE>, marking a milestone for the group that has campaigned over <DATE>the years</DATE> for the abolition of nuclear weapons.The group, founded in <DATE>1956</DATE>, was awarded the prize \"for its efforts to achieve a world free of nuclear weapons and for demonstrating through witness testimony that nuclear weapons must never be used again,\" the <ORG>Norwegian</ORG> <ORG>Nobel Committee</ORG> said.It is the <ORDINAL>second</ORDINAL> time a <NORP><GPE>Japan</GPE>ese</NORP> person or organization has received <WORK_OF_ART>the Nobel Peace Prize</WORK_OF_ART> since <DATE>1974</DATE> when it was given to former Prime Minister <PERSON>Eisaku Sato</PERSON>, who introduced <GPE>Japan</GPE>'s <CARDINAL>three</CARDINAL> non-nuclear principles of not possessing, producing or allowing nuclear weapons on its territory.\"The extraordinary efforts of <PERSON>Nihon Hidankyo</PERSON> and other representatives of the <ORG>Hibakusha</ORG> have contributed greatly to the establishment of the nuclear taboo.It is therefore alarming that <DATE>today</DATE> this taboo against the use of nuclear weapons is under pressure,\" the committee added.<GPE>Russia</GPE> has threatened to use nuclear arms since it began its invasion of <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> in <DATE>February 2022</DATE>, while fears have intensified amid mounting confrontation between <GPE>Israel</GPE>, a nuclear state, and <GPE>Iran</GPE>, which has been working on developing such a weapons capability.Meanwhile, momentum toward abolishment of nuclear weapons has stalled in <DATE>recent years</DATE>, as member parties at the <LAW>Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty</LAW> review conference failed to adopt a report in <DATE>2022</DATE> due to opposition from <GPE>Russia</GPE>, the <ORDINAL>second</ORDINAL> straight time since <DATE>2015</DATE>.\"Please abolish nuclear weapons while we are still alive,\" said <PERSON>Toshiyuki Mimaki</PERSON>, head of <ORG>the Hiroshima Prefectural Confederation of A-bomb Sufferers Organizations</ORG>, after the announcement.The <GPE>U.S.</GPE> bombings of <GPE>Hiroshima</GPE> on <DATE>Aug. 6, 1945</DATE>, and <EVENT>Nagasaki</EVENT> <DATE>three</DATE> days later are estimated to have killed <CARDINAL>around 210,000</CARDINAL> people by <DATE>the end of that year</DATE>.<GPE>Japan</GPE> surrendered <DATE>six days</DATE> after the <GPE>Nagasaki</GPE> bombing, bringing an end to <EVENT>World War II</EVENT>.Until the formation of <ORG>Hidankyo</ORG>, atomic bomb survivors, or hibakusha in <LANGUAGE><GPE>Japan</GPE>ese</LANGUAGE>, had been largely living in silence, struggling with health problems, poverty and social discrimination in <GPE>Japan</GPE>.\"I can picture the faces of my predecessors who had wished for there never to be an incident that would lead to the creation of hibakusha ever again,\" <PERSON>Sueichi Kido</PERSON>, the group's secretary general, said of the win.\"I believe they would view <DATE>the long years</DATE> we've been fighting with sincerity,\" he added.Hibakusha were encouraged to stand up as anti-nuclear sentiment was rekindled among the public after a <GPE>U.S.</GPE> hydrogen bomb test on <LOC>Bikini Atoll</LOC> in <GPE>the Marshall Islands</GPE> in <DATE>1954</DATE>, which exposed the local population and crew members of a <NORP>Japanese</NORP> tuna fishing boat to radioactive fallout.As part of the organization, atomic bomb survivors began campaigning to change the status quo, setting <CARDINAL>two</CARDINAL> main objectives -- the abolition of nuclear weapons and the winning of state compensation for the damage caused by the bombing.Their activities have resulted in the enactment of laws to provide medical and other support for survivors.<ORG>Hidankyo</ORG> has also sent survivors to speak in various countries and at international events about the devastating consequences of atomic weapons in a bid to promote a world free of nuclear weapons.<NORP>Japanese</NORP> Prime Minister <PERSON>Shigeru Ishiba</PERSON> said, \"It is extremely meaningful for the award to be given to a group that has dedicated <DATE>many years</DATE> toward the abolition of nuclear weapons.\"In <DATE>2017</DATE>, <ORG>the International Campaign to Abolish Nuclear Weapons</ORG>, or <ORG>ICAN</ORG>, was awarded the peace prize for their efforts that led to the adoption of the <ORG>U.N.</ORG> treaty outlawing nuclear weapons."
"<GPE>Japan</GPE>'s National Daily Since 1922 <DATE>October 11, 2024</DATE> (<GPE>Mainichi</GPE> <GPE>Japan</GPE>)      <GPE>VIENTIANE</GPE> (<GPE>Kyodo</GPE>) -- Major <LOC>Asia-Pacific</LOC> countries remained divergent <DATE>Friday</DATE> over <GPE>Russia</GPE>'s prolonged war in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> and key regional issues, such as tensions in <LOC>the South China Sea</LOC> and <GPE>North Korea's</GPE> missile development, during their leaders' meeting in <GPE>Laos</GPE>.Among <CARDINAL>18</CARDINAL> countries joining <EVENT>the East Asia Summit</EVENT> in the capital, <GPE>Vientiane</GPE>, <GPE>the United States</GPE>, <GPE>Japan</GPE> and some other nations criticized <GPE>Moscow</GPE>'s invasion of <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>, saying it is a clear violation of international law, according to participants.<NORP><GPE>Russia</GPE>n</NORP> Foreign Minister <PERSON>Sergey Lavrov</PERSON> rapped <GPE>the United States</GPE> and its allies for trying to isolate themselves from <GPE>Russia</GPE> and <GPE>China</GPE> and draw as many <ORG>ASEAN</ORG> members as possible to their side, <GPE>Russia</GPE>'s <ORG>Tass</ORG> news agency said.Some member states expressed wariness over \"coercive actions\" in <LOC>the South <GPE>China</GPE> Sea</LOC>, where <GPE>China</GPE> and its neighbors have been engaged in territorial disputes and stressed the importance of maintaining peace and stability across <LOC>the Taiwan Strait</LOC>, the participants said.Countries such as <GPE>Japan</GPE> and <GPE>South Korea</GPE> also raised concerns over <GPE>North Korea's</GPE> closer military cooperation with <GPE>Russia</GPE>.The <ORG>EAS</ORG> groups the <CARDINAL>10-member</CARDINAL> <ORG>Association of Southeast Asian Nations</ORG> and <CARDINAL>eight</CARDINAL> other countries, with participants also including newly elected <NORP>Japanese</NORP> Prime Minister <PERSON>Shigeru Ishiba</PERSON>, <NORP>Chinese</NORP> Premier <PERSON>Li Qiang</PERSON> and <GPE>U.S.</GPE> Secretary of <ORG>State</ORG> <PERSON>Antony Blinken</PERSON>.<PERSON>Blinken</PERSON> told a press conference following the meeting that he underscored the importance of upholding \"the freedom of navigation and overflight\" in <LOC>the South China Sea</LOC> and addressed <GPE>North Korea's</GPE> \"dangerous and destabilizing behavior.\"<PERSON>Ishiba</PERSON> said unilateral attempts to change the status quo by force are \"unacceptable anywhere in the world\" and called for a peaceful solution to a territorial dispute between <GPE>China</GPE> and the <GPE>Philippines</GPE> in the South <GPE>China</GPE> Sea, where their vessels frequently confront each other.<GPE>China</GPE>'s <PERSON>Li</PERSON> urged countries outside the region to respect and support <GPE>China</GPE>'s joint efforts with neighboring countries to maintain peace and stability in the South <GPE>China</GPE> Sea, the official <ORG>Xinhua News Agency</ORG> said.<PERSON>Li</PERSON> claimed at the gathering that <GPE>Beijing</GPE> has \"always been committed to abiding by international law\" and insisted on resolving differences in <LOC>the South China Sea</LOC> through dialogue and consultation, <ORG>Xinhua</ORG> said.The rift between <NORP>Western</NORP> nations and <GPE>China</GPE> and <GPE>Russia</GPE> has been widening over <GPE>Beijing</GPE>'s expanding military activities in the <LOC>East</LOC> and South <GPE>China</GPE> seas and the war in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE> launched by <GPE>Moscow</GPE> in <DATE>February 2022</DATE>.<GPE>Washington</GPE> claims <GPE>China</GPE> is supporting the <NORP>Russian</NORP> defense industrial base and has urged <GPE>Beijing</GPE> to desist.The <LOC>West</LOC> \"seeks to make <ORG>ASEAN</ORG> its main partner and direct this partnership against the interests of <GPE>Russia</GPE> and <GPE>China</GPE>,\" <PERSON>Lavrov</PERSON> was quoted by <ORG>Tass</ORG> as saying at a press conference.<NORP>South Korean</NORP> President <PERSON>Yoon Suk Yeol</PERSON> said, meanwhile, military cooperation between <GPE>Russia</GPE> and <GPE>North Korea</GPE> is \"prolonging the war\" in <GPE>Ukraine</GPE>, while he called for leaders' sustained attention to <GPE>Pyongyang</GPE>'s violation of human rights, including the past abduction of <NORP>Japanese</NORP> nationals, according to his office.The <ORG>EAS</ORG> comprises <ORG>ASEAN</ORG> -- <GPE>Brunei</GPE>, <GPE>Cambodia</GPE>, <GPE>Indonesia</GPE>, <GPE>Laos</GPE>, <GPE>Malaysia</GPE>, <GPE>Myanmar</GPE>, the <GPE>Philippines</GPE>, <GPE>Singapore</GPE>, <GPE>Thailand</GPE> and <GPE>Vietnam</GPE> -- plus <GPE>Australia</GPE>, <GPE>China</GPE>, <GPE>India</GPE>, <GPE>Japan</GPE>, <GPE>New Zealand</GPE>, <GPE>Russia</GPE>, <GPE>South Korea</GPE> and <GPE>the United States</GPE>."
